Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection, 1931-1964
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Price, Lillard and A.R. Whitfield, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Lillard Price is from Tubac, Arizona... A.R. Whitfield is from Nogales, Arizona... Guitar medley (Lillard Price) -- La Rumba (A.R. Whitfield... "who learned it in San Luis Potasi 65 years ago") -- A Little star shining for you (A.R. Whitfield) -- Ragtime clock (A.R. Whitfield... "learned from a musicial supplement to St. Louis Globe-Democrat about 65 years ago") -- Two sweethearts (Lillard Price) -- Little rosewood casket (Lillard Price) -- Strawberry roan (Lillard Price); SWF PRE1980.1/D.138
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Carrillo School Children, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; Tucson, AZ. Sung by Carrillo School children, solo voices: Angie Garcia and Vicki Canez... Toquen los pitos -- Carra Carmela -- Lullaby -- Nos despedimos contentos -- Noche de Pas -- Quien de las Posada -- Hermildes Regregrinos -- Operegrina graciada -- Abrid vuestras puertas -- Entre Regina --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.139 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Mariachi Jalisciense, 1 sound disc, analog, 45 rpm, 7 in.; Palma Records. Bienvenida (Manuel Palma Parro) -- Josefina y Manuel -- La Tragedia de President Kennedy (Enrique Pino) -- Josefina Cuestas --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.140 (7in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hilton, L.M.and Paul Anderson, 1946; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Ogden and Woods Cross, UT. Fife Mormon Recording. Hand cart song (L.M. Hilton, Ogden) -- Don't you marry the Mormon boys (Paul Anderson, Woods Cross) -- The Gospel news (L.M. Hilton, Ogden) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.141
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Huntsman, Jetta, Mary H. Leavitt, L.M. Hilton and Myron Crandall, 1946; 1947; 1 sound disc, analog,; Ogden and St. George, UT., Fife Mormon Recording. In the midst of these awful Mormons (Jetta Huntsman, St. George) -- None can preach the gospel like the Mormons (Mary H. Leavitt, St. George) -- Echo Canyon (L.M. Hilton, Ogden) -- Painting clouds of sunshine (composed and sung by Myron Crandall, Ogden) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.142
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections,Kinmann, Matt, February 15, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Old Fiddler's Contest, Tucson, AZ. Recorded by Charles Wiley... Breakdowns: Turkey in the straw -- Durand's hornpipe -- Saturday night waltz --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.143
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A., May, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Mrs. John A. Ray from Mesa, Arizona... Little black like me ("Are there any angels black like me?") -- The Grasshopper song -- There was a queer little man --; Frances Gillmor; SWF PRE1980.1/D.144
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections,Ray, Mrs. John A. and Mrs. Lurlene Ray Russell, May, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Performances from Mesa, Arizona... Jack Frost (Mrs. John A. Ray) -- The Little cherry tree (Mrs. John A. Ray) -- Rover (Mrs. Lurlene Ray Russell) -- Robin redbreast (Mrs. Lurlene Ray Russell) -- Songs of the five senses (Mrs. John A. Ray) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.145
- Songs of Lebanon, Syria and Jordan, Bulos, Afif, 1961; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y. Folkways Records, Ar-rozana (The Rozana) -- Hayyin Darb-is-seif (The Fall of the sword is easier) -- Yamil'abaya (Maiden beautiful) -- Lamman bada yatathana (When my love languished) -- Al-loma (Instrumental) -- Tafti Hindi (Indian Taffeta) -- Mash'al -- Ala Dal'ona (The Spoilt one) -- 'Al Yadi (The Valley) -- Ali-'snayyin -- Ya Ghzayyel (O Gazelle) -- Bint-esh-shalibiyya (The Pretty one) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.146
- American music - folk: Records from the collection of Harry Smith, Ballads, no. 1-2, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. Henry Lee (Dick Justice) -- Fatal flower garden (Nelstone's Hawaiians) -- The House carpenter (Clarance Ashley) -- Drunkard's special (Coley Jones) -- Old lady and the devil (Bill and Belle) -- The Butcher boy (Buell Kazee) -- The Wagoners end (Buell Kazell) -- King Kong kitchie kitchie ki-me-o ("Chubby" Parker) -- Old shoes and leggins (Uncle Eck Dunford) -- Willie Moore (Burnett and Rutherford) -- A Lazy farmer boy (Buster Carter and Preston Young) -- Peg and awl (Carolina Tar Heels) -- Ommie Wise (G.B. Grayson) -- My name is John Johanna (Kelly Harrell) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.148
- American music - folk: Records from the collection of Harry Smith, Ballads, no. 3-4, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. Bandit colt younger (Edward L. Crain) -- Charles Giteau (Kelly Harrell) -- John Hardy was a desperate little man (The Carter family) -- Gonna die with my hammer in my hand (Williamson Brothers and Cuny) -- Stackalee (Frank Hutchison) -- White Horse blues ( Charlie Poole with the North Carolina Ramblers) -- Frankie (Mississippi John Hurt) -- When that great ship went down (William and Varsey Smith) -- Engine One-Forty-Three (The Carter family) -- Kassie Jones, two parts (Furry Lewis) -- Mississippi Boweavil blues (The Mashed Marvel) -- Got the farm land blues (The Carolina Tar Heels) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.149
- American music - folk: Records from the collection of Harry Smith, Dances, no. 1, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. Sail away lady (Uncle Bunt Stephens) -- The Wild wagoner (J.W. Day) -- Wake up Jacob (Prince Albert Hunt's Texas Ramblers) -- La Danseuse - Fox trot (De'ma Lachney and Blind Uncle Gaspard) -- Georgia stomp (Andrew and Jim Baxter) -- Brilliancy medley (Eck Robertson and family) -- Indian war whoop (Floyd Ming and his Pep-steppers) -- Old country stomp (Henry Thomas) -- Old dog Blue (Jim Jackson) -- Saut Crapaud - Fox trot (Columbus Freeze) -- Arcadian one step (Joseph Falcon) -- Home sweet home (Breaux Freres) -- Newport blues (Cincinnati Jug Band) -- Moonshiner's dance, part 1 (Frank Cloutier and Victoria Cale Orchestra) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.150
- American music - folk: Records from the collection of Harry Smith, Religious, no. 1-2, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. Must be born again (Rev. J.M. Gates) -- Oh death where is they sting (Rev. R.M. Gates) -- Rocky road (Alabama Sacred Harp Singers) -- Present joys (Alabama Sacred Harp Singers) -- This song of love (Middle Georgia Singing Convention) -- Judgement (Rev. Sister Mary Nelson) -- He got better things for you (Memphis Sanctified Singers) -- Since I laid my burden down (Elders McIntorsch & Edwards) -- John the Baptist (Rev. Moses Mason) -- Dry bones (Bascom Lamar Lunsford) -- John the Revelator (Blind Willie Johnson) -- Little Moses (The Carter family) -- Shine on me (Ernst Phipps and his Holiness Singers) -- Fifty miles of elbow room (Rev. F.W. McGee) -- I'm in the battle field for my Lord (Rev. D.C. Rice and his Sanctified Congregation) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.151
- American music - folk: Records from the collection of Harry Smith, Songs, no. 1-2, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. The coo coo bird (Clarence Ashley) -- East Virginia (Buell Kazee) -- Minglewood blues (Cannons Jug Stompers) -- I woke up one morning (Didier Herbert) -- James Alley blues (Richard "Rabbit" Brown) -- Sugar baby ("Dock" Boggs) -- I wish I was a mole in the ground (Bascom Lamar Lunsford) -- The Mountaineer's courtship (Mr. and Mrs. Ernest V. Stoneman) -- The Spainish merchant's daughter (Stoneman family) -- Bob Lee Junior blues (Memphis Jug Band) -- Single girl, married girl (Carter family) -- Le Vieux soulard et sa femme (Clemo Breaux & Joseph Falcon) -- Expressman blues (John Estes) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.152
- Behind these walls, Ferguson, Hank, 1962; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Huntington, VT., Folk Legacy Records, Inc. I'm not living (Ferguson) -- The Walls -- Get a little dirt on your hands -- One life's as long as any man can live (Ferguson) -- Shackles and chains -- Thunder Road -- Trouble just got in my way (Ferguson) -- Busted -- You ain't heard nothing yet -- Waiting for the train -- The Wreck of Old # 9 -- Jolly time farmer -- Rich girl, poor girl -- The Wreck of Old 97 -- Wabash Cannonball -- Nine pound hammer -- Long black veil -- Interstate 40 --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.154
- Anglo-American folk songs, Nye, Hermes, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Sung by Hermes Nye with guitar... Tomorrow is St. Valentine's Day -- A North country maid -- King Arthur had three sons -- Earl Richard -- Greenland fishery -- Earl of Murray -- John Peer -- The Mermaid (Landlubber) -- The Red herring -- The Bailiff's daughter --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.155
- The Folksongs of Britain: Volume One, Songs of Courtship, 1961; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Lochrae Music Corporation. Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax, editors... Green grow the laurels -- The False bride -- Our wedding day -- When a man's in love -- Ailein Duinn -- Bonnie Kate -- Old grey beard newly shaven -- Sweet primeroses -- The Coolin -- Shule aroon -- The Mountain streams -- The Brown thorn -- As I roved out -- The Magpie's nest -- Dame Durden -- Casadh an Tsugain -- Twisting the hay-rope -- My darling ploughman boy -- The False young man -- I'm a young bonnie lassie -- No, John, no -- Abhainn na sead -- Bogie's bonnie belle --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.156
- The Folksongs of Britain: Volume Two, Songs of seduction, 1961; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Caedmon Records, Inc. Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax, editors... As I walked through Dublin City -- The Light Drag'on -- The Orkney style of courtship -- The Cuckoo's nest -- The Soldier and the lady -- Molly, put the kettle on -- Never wed an old man -- The maid of Australia -- The Merchant's son and the beggar's daughter -- The Bold English Navy -- Cruising round Yarmouth -- The Nutting girl --The Bonnie wee lassie girl who never said no -- Bundle and go -- Blow the candle out -- The Foggy dew -- Toorna-ma-goon -- Rolling in the ryegrass -- The Jolly tinker -- The Long peggin'awl -- The Thrashing machine -- Up to the rigs of London town -- The Wind blew the bonnie lassie's plaidie awa -- The Cunning cobbler --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.157
- The Folk songs of Britain: Volume 3, Jack of all trades, 1961; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Lochrae Music Corporation. Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax, editors ... The Jovial tradesmen -- The Roving journeymen -- The Candlelight fisherman -- The Canny shepherd laddie -- The Dairy maid -- Green brooms -- Gruel -- The Jug of punch -- The Gresford disaster -- The Jolly miller -- The Irish washerwoman -- Farewell to whiskey -- The Roving ploughboy -- The Buchan miller -- Fagan the cobbler -- The Ould piper -- Sweep, chimney sweep -- The Mason's apron -- Rhynie -- The Tailor by trade -- The Wee weaver -- Jim the Carter lad -- Drumdelgie -- The Merry haymakers -- I'll mend your pots and kettles --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.158
- The Folksongs of Britain: Volume 4, The Child ballads, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y. Caedmon Records Inc. Captain Wedderman's courtship -- The Twa brothers -- Lord Bateman -- Lord Thomas and Fair Allen -- Lord Lovell -- Lord Gregory -- Barbara Allen -- George Collins -- Cruel Lincoln -- The Prickelly bush -- The Elfin knight (An Acre of land) -- The Elfin knight (Strawberry Lane) -- The False knight on the road -- Lady Isabel and the elf knight -- The Twa sisters -- Lord Randall -- Edward -- King Orfeo -- The Cruel mother -- The Broomfield wager --; Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax; SWF PRE1980.1/D.159
- The Folksongs of Britain: Volume 5, The Child ballads, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Caedmon Records Inc. The Royal forester -- The Baffled knight -- Johnie Cock -- Robin Hood and Little John -- The Jew's garden -- The Battle of Harlaw -- The Four Maries -- The Gypsy laddie -- Georgie -- The Dowie Dens of Yarrow -- Glenlogie -- The Grey cock -- Henry Martin -- Lang Johnny More -- Willie's fate -- Our goodman -- The Farmer's curst wife -- The Jolly beggar -- The Auld beggarman -- The Keach in the creel -- The Golden vanity - The Trooper lad; Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax; SWF PRE1980.1/D.160
  Original Collector: Peter Kennedy and Alan Lomax
- Broadside ballads - London: 1600-1700, MacColl, Ewan, 1962; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Sung by Ewan MacColl... Accompaniments by: Peggy Seeger, guitar, banjo and autoharp; Alf Edwards, English concertina, ocarina and tabor; Alfie Kahn, piccolo, flute and tin whistle... Room for company (piccolo and tabor) -- Pity's lamentation (guitar and flute) -- There's nothing to be had without money (concertina, flute and guitar) -- The Midwife's ghost (autoharp) -- A Merry progress to London (unaccompanied) --London's lottery (guitar and flute) -- London mourning in ashes (concertina) -- King Lear and his three daughters (flute, concertina and guitar) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.161
- Blues with Brownie McGhee and guitar. McGhee, Brownie, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Recorded by Moses Asch... Careless love -- Good morning blues -- Sporting life -- Me and Sonny -- Pawnshop blues -- Move Kansas City -- Betty and Dupree --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.162 (10in.)
- Lord Invader and the Trinidad Caribbean Orchestra, Calypso, with Lord Invader and the Trinidad Caribbean Orchestra, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Barrack-room scandal -- Reincarnation -- Brooklyn, Brooklyn! -- Barbados -- Brown skin girl -- 29, Port of Spain -- Labor Day -- Jonah --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.163 (10in.)
- Christmas with Mahalia Jackson, Jackson, Mahalia, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Edgewood Corp. Silent night - Holy night (3:00) -- Walking to Jerusalem (3:04) -- Go tell it on the mountain (3:06) -- I can put my trust in Jesus (3:13) -- God spoke to me (2:50) -- His eye in on the sparrow (3:25) -- The Lord's prayer (3:00) -- Come to Jesus (3:18) -- He's my light (2:55) -- City called Heaven (3:20) -- Bless this house (3:13) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.164
- La Fleche d'or d'Haiti, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Haiti. Vocals by A. Dorismond and G. French... Rythmn: Cadence Rampa... Ti tata -- Belle martiniquaise -- Nanotte cherie -- Carnaval -- Retour de la cadence -- Crainte d'amour -- Ti cameau -- Pa triche -- Lucienne -- Toujours plus femme -- A l'amour -- En passant a Porto-Rico --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.165
- Dust bowl ballads, Guthrie, Woody, 1964; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. All music and text written and performed by Woody Guthrie... Talkin' dust bowl blues -- Blowin' down this road -- Do re mi -- Dust cain't kill me -- Tom Joad, I -- Tom Joad, II -- The Great dust storm -- Dusty old dust -- Dust bowl refugee -- Dust pneumonia blues -- I ain't got no home in this world no more -- Vigilante men --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.166
- The English and Scottish popular ballads, Vol. 3, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd, 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. The Battle of Harlaw -- The Dover sailor -- Among the blue flowers and the yellow -- The Golden vanity -- The Douglas tragedy -- The Dowie Dens of Yarrow -- Robin Hood and the Bishop of Hereford -- The Gaindner child -- Gil Morice --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.167
- The English and Scottish popular ballads, Vol. 3, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd, 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. The Crafty farmer -- Gipsies-o -- Lang Johnnie More -- Long lankin -- The Beggar laddie -- Rob Roy -- The Cherry tree -- The Heir o'Lynne -- Hughie Graeme --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.168
- The English and Scottish popular ballads, Vol. 4, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd, 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. Jock the leg -- The Daemon lover -- The Earl of Aboyne -- Scarborough fair -- Lord Gregory -- The Bonnie Earl O'Murray -- Henry Martin -- Clyde's water -- The Lover's ghost --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.169
- The English and Scottish popular ballads, Vol. 4, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd, 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. The Burning o'Auchendoun -- The Banks of Green Willow -- Bessie Bell and Mary Gray -- Bold Sir Rylas -- Captain Wedderburn's courtship -- Captain Ward and the rainbow -- Dives and Lazarus -- The Cruel mother -- Lord Thomas and fair Eleanor --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.170
- The English and Scottish popular ballads: The Child ballads, Vol. 6, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd, 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. The Crafty farmer -- Gipsies-o -- Lang Johnnie More -- Long lankin -- The Beggar laddie -- Rob Roy -- The Cherry tree -- The Heir o'Lynne -- Hughie Graeme --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.171
- The English and Scottish popular ballads: The Child ballads, Vol. 7, MacColl, Ewan and A.L. Lloyd, 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Bill Grauer Productions. Jock the leg -- The Daemon lover -- The Earl of Aboyne -- Scarborough fair -- Lord Gregory -- The Bonnie Earl O'Murray -- Henry Martin -- Clyde's water -- The Lover's ghost --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.172
- The Cowboy: His songs, ballads & brag talk, 1959; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Services Corp. Edited by Kenneth S. Goldstein... Morning grub holler -- The Round-up cook -- The Dally roper's song -- I ride an old paint -- Some cowboy brag talk -- Little Joe the wrangler -- Utah Carroll -- Old iron pants Pete -- The Saddle bum -- Strawberry roan -- I ain't got no use for the women -- Blood on the saddle -- The Ridge running roan -- Roll on, little dogies -- The Hangman's song --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.173
- The cowboy: His songs, ballads & brag talk, Jackson, Harry, 1959; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Services Corp. Edited by Kenneth S. Goldstein... Boastin' cowboy -- Tying a knot in the devil's tale -- Clayton Boone -- Old Blue was a gray horse -- Little Joe the wrangler's sister Nell -- The Gal I left behind -- Zebra dun -- When the work's all done this fall -- The Pot wrassler -- Streets of Laredo -- Windy Bill -- Cowboy talking to a bucking horse -- As I went wallking one morning for pleasure -- Cowboy Jack -- Jack of diamonds -- I'm gonna leave old Texas now --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.174
- Favorite gospel songs, West, Harry and Jeanie West, 1957; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Recorded by Kenneth S. Goldstein...When our Lord shall come again -- Matthew twenty-four -- What are they doing in heaven today -- Sweet bye and bye -- Walking my Lord up Calvary's hill -- He'll set your fields on fire -- Campin' in Canaan's land -- The Man of Galilee -- Oh, hide you in the blood -- Amazing grace -- Preach the gospel -- Only one step more -- Thirty pieces of silver -- The Sea of life -- I'm gonna let it shine -- I'm only on a journey here --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.175
- Folk music of Haiti, 1951; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records and Services Corp. Recorded in Haiti by Harold Courlander... Pile pied'm (Morgina Lavache) -- M'pas bwa m'pas mange (Libera Borderau and Ti Yogan) -- Ogoun Balindjo (La France Belvue) -- Ezilie Wedo (La France Belvue) -- La Famille li fai ca (Lina Hibbert) -- Moundongue oh ye ye ye (La France Belvue) -- Ramis loin loin (D:merv:1 servers) -- Ou pas we m'innocent (Aleanne Francois) -- Mainin'm alle (Ti Yogan and Morgina Lavache) -- Cote yo, cote yo (Libera Borderau) -- Crapeau Tingele (Libera Borderau) -- Balance ya ya (Edgar Dersoler) -- Trois fe (Christophe Oxilas) -- Spirit conversation (Cult priest at Leogane) -- General Brise (La France Belvue) -- Mayousse -- Paulette (Sigbrien Bellis and Veneise Maclise) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.176
- Folk music of Kashmir, 1962; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records. Recordings and notes by E. Bhavnian... Santur -- Title music -- Title music -- Love and the beauty of nature -- Instrumental -- Song of the boatmen -- Love duet -- Song of the nightingale -- Instrumental -- Romantic music -- Song of the silk worm -- Beautiful Kashmir -- Song of spring --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.177
- Songs of the Michigan lumberjacks, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in; Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Edited by E.C. Beck... Once more a-lumbering go -- Michigan I-O -- The Jam on Gerry's rocks, I -- The Jam on Gerry's rocks, II -- Jack Haggerty -- The Little brown bulls -- Lumberjack's alphabet -- The Falling of the pine -- The Wild Mustard River -- Turner's camp on the Chippewa -- Johnny Carroll's camp --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.178
- Songs of the Papago, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Frances Densmore... Copied from cylinders recorded in 1920 from the Smithsonian - Densmore Collection from the Archive of American Folk Songs.. Songs connected with legends: Song of earth magician when disappearing in the ground -- Song of brown buzzard after killing elder brother -- Song before emerging from ashes hill -- Song to put eagle to sleep -- Song of the old women who attended elder brother -- Four fires on the ground -- The girls are approaching -- Song to make the boy invisible -- Songs connected with ceremonies: The Dwelling place of the sun -- Each singer wears a white feather -- Song of the watchers -- Song during rain divination -- A Blue wind -- Song connected with expeditions to obtain salt: The Wind blows from the sea -- Songs connected with treatment of the sick: Sandy loam fields -- Out of the mountains -- Song to a little yellow wasp -- Song of the dawn -- Dream songs: White Mountain birds were singing -- A Black crow -- War songs: Song concerning a wounded Apache -- The Little captive children -- The Eagle is talking -- Song of the kicking-ball race: We must run -- Miscellaneous: I met a Mexican --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.179
- Folksongs of courting and complaint, Seeger, Peggy and Clark Weissman, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Sung by Peggy Seeger, with 5-string banjo... Clark Weissman, guitar... Whistle, daughter, whistle -- When I was single -- The House carpenter -- When first unto this country a stranger I came -- All of her answers to me were no -- Young man who wouldn't hoe corn -- The Wagoners lad -- Long lonesome road -- The Butcher's boy -- The Old maid's song -- Katy cruel -- Leatherwing bat --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.180
- Mexican folk songs, Cruz, Alfonso, 1958; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Recorded in Oaxaca, Mexico... El Yerbero (The Herb-seller) -- Babalu -- Rojociano el Guapangero (The Guasteca is in mourning) -- Echame a mi la culpa (Put the blame on me) -- La Falta un clavo a mi cruz (There is a nail missing in my cross) -- Deja que salza la luna (Let the moon rise) -- La Tortolita -- Ya tu veras (You will see) -- Carinito azucarado (Little sweetheart) -- Mere cumbe (Last night I dreamed of you) -- Tehuanyepec -- La Zandunja -- Cucucurucucu, paloma (Little dove) -- La Molienda y la culebra (The cane harvest and the snake) -- Cachito --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.181